Let's look at a more realistic image this time, for example,
这次 我们来看一个更真实的图像
this 64 by 64 pixel image of a car.
这是一辆汽车的 64×64 像素图像
And let's compute the gradient magnitudes and directions at each pixel.
让我们计算每个像素的梯度幅值和方向
Now, instead of using all these individual values,
我们不会逐像素使用这些梯度
let's group them up into small cells, say, of size 8 by 8 pixels each.
而是统计每个小的单元格中的梯度 假设每个单元格大小为 8×8 像素
Inside each cell is where the magic happens.
在每个单元格内有神奇的事情会发生
You will compute a histogram of gradient directions or
你可以计算单元格内 64 个
orientations from each of the 64 pixels within the cell.
梯度的直方图
The gradient samples are distributed into, say, nine orientation bins, and
梯度样本按照方向被分布到直方图的 9 个柱 (orientation bins) 中
summed up.
然后求和
You typically won't need any more accuracy at this small scale.
样本规模不大的时候 通常不需要很高的精度
The resulting histogram will look somewhat like this.
所得到的直方图看起来大概是这样
A better way to visualize the histogram for
将还有一个更好的可视化方法
an individual cell would be to add up the contributions for samples in
就是在把各个梯度按照方向分类放置
each orientation bin to get a sort of star with arms of different lengths.
从而得到图中所示的各方向矢量大小不同的星形
The direction with the longest arm is the dominant gradient direction
最长矢量的方向
in the cell.
代表这个单元格的主梯度方向
Note that the histogram is not strictly a count of the number of samples in each
注意 这个直方图并不是
direction.
对每个方向梯度数量进行求和
Instead, you sum up the gradient magnitude of each sample.
你需要计算的是所有像素梯度的矢量和
So stronger gradients contribute more weight to their orientation bin, and
因此 梯度幅值越大 对该方向对应的直方图柱的贡献就越大
the effect of small random gradients due to noise, etc., is reduced.
从而减少了例如噪声引入的随机梯度影响
In other words, each pixel in the image gets a vote on which histogram bin it
换句话说 图像中的每个像素根据其梯度方向
belongs in based on the gradient direction at that position.
对直方图中对应方向的柱进行投票
But the strength or
但是每一票的强度 或称为权重
weight of that vote depends on the gradient magnitude at that pixel.
取决于该像素梯度的幅值
When you do this for all the cells,
当你对所有单元格投票后
you begin to see a representation of the original structure emerge.
你开始看到原始结构轮廓的出现
As demonstrated with simpler shapes before,
正如此前采用更简单的形状演示的那样
something like this can be used as a signature for a given shape.
这个轮廓可以用作给定形状的特征
This is known as a histogram of oriented gradients, or HoG feature.
它被称为梯度方向直方图 或 HoG 特征
The main advantage now is that you have built in the ability to accept small
这种方法的主要优势在于
variations in the shape, while keeping the signature distinct enough.
你可以在形状发生小幅变化同时 保持形状特征的独特性
How accommodating or sensitive the feature is can be tweaked by
可以通过调整各个参数 来改变特征对于小幅变化的适应程度
varying parameters such as the number of orientation bins, grid of cells,
这些参数包括 柱的数量 单元格格数
cell sizes, adding any overlap between cells, etc.
单元格大小、以及是否在单元格之间增加重叠部分等
A number of other enhancements are used in practice, including normalizing for
在实际应用中 我们可以使用许多其他增强功能
intensity across small blocks of cells, etc.
包括对每个单元格内的梯度幅值进行归一化处理
For a more in depth discussion of histogram of oriented gradients and
如果想更深入地了解 HoG
how it has been used for
以及如何用它来进行人的检测
detecting people, please refer to the link in the instructor notes.
请参考讲师注释中的链接